Guide to the Records of the Institute of African American Affairs RG.9.8
New York University Archives
- Series IV. Audiovisual Recordings, 1963-2007; 50 Linear Feet in 44 record cartons, 3 card boxes, 2 cassette boxes, and 4 flat boxes.; 627 sound tape reels; 251 audiocassettes; 267 VHS; 32 Betacam; 153 U-matic; 4 DVCAM; 54 MiniDV; 1 Hi8
  - Subseries IV.B. Events Recordings, 1970-2007; 34.50 Linear Feet in 29 record cartons, 2 cassette boxes, 1 card box, and 4 flat boxes.; 267 VHS; 251 audiocassettes; 168 sound tape reels; 153 U-matic; 54 MiniDV; 32 Betacam; 4 DVCAM; 1 Hi8
    - Black Contribution to the West -- Tapes 1-3, 1982-11-08; cuid15878 (Box 38, Reel cuid15878A, cuid15878B, cuid15878C)
      Housing annotations: "Tape 3 of 3 suggests lecture ends at 12:50, Question and answer period follows"
    - Black Contribution to the West -- Tapes 1-3, 1982-11-15; cuid17309 (Box 47, Reel cuid17309A, cuid17309B, cuid17309C)
    - Black Contribution to American Business & Industry -- Tapes 1-4, 1983-02-04; cuid17314 (Box 47, Reel cuid17314A, cuid17314B, cuid17314C, cuid17314D)
    - Ivan Dixon -- Black Filmmakers Hall of Fame Seminar, 1983-02-23 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0741)
    - Percy Sutton Lecture with Pierre Sutton, 1983-04-13; cuid15874 (Box 38, Reel cuid15874)
      Housing annotations: "School or Division: Institutional Facilities; Department: Communications"
    - Black Women's Conference -- Tapes 1-4, 1983-04-30; cuid17278 (Box 42, Reel cuid17278A, cuid17278B, cuid17278C, cuid17278D)
    - Community Lectures Series -- Tapes 1-6, 1983-05-17; cuid15875 (Box 38, Reel cuid15875A, cuid15875B, cuid15875C, cuid15875D, cuid15875E, cuid15875F)
    - Poets Honor Larry Neal -- Tapes 1-5, 1983-07-15; cuid15868 (Box 37, Reel cuid15868A,cuid15868B, Box 47, Reel cuid15868C,cuid15868D, cuid15868E)
      Housing annotations: "IAAA, Loeb Student Center, E and L Auditorium"
    - Warrington Hudlin -- NYC, 1983-08-03 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0764)
    - "Celebration: Experiences in African Art" by Catti -- Tape 3, 1984-02-15; cuid17280 (Box 42, Reel cuid17280)
    - Black Vietnam Veteran Conference: Judge Bruce Wright -- T.O.P., Tapes 1-4, 1984-05-05; cuid17313 (Box 47, Reel cuid17313A, cuid17313B, cuid17313C, cuid17313D)
    - Catti at Eisner and Lubin Auditorium -- Tapes 1-3, 1985-02-21; cuid15873 (Box 38, Reel cuid15873A, cuid15873B, cuid15873C)
    - Gallery Talk -- James A. Snead, 1985-06-20 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0693)
    - Community Lecture Series: Paule Marshall, 1985-10-16 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0597)
    - Interview of St. Clair Bourne -- NYC, 1986-07-04-1986-07-12 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0509)
    - St. Clair Bourne, 1988-02-23 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0531)
    - Toni C.H. Gevina, 1988-04-19 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0532)
    - Birth of Black Cinema Symposium Sponsored by Toni Morrison -- SUNY Albany, 1988-11-17-1988-11-19 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0523 -- 9-8.0526, Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0694)
    - Miles Davis Radio Project, circa 1989-1991 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0587, Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0510, 9-8.0517)
    - Prisons of Image, 1989 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0256)
    - Celebration of Margaret Walker, 1990 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0139)
    - University of Pennsylvania Center for Study of Black Literature and Culture, 1990-03-16-1990-03-17 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0682 -- 9-8.0692)
    - Jewish Film Festival, 1992-07-31 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0529 -- 9-8.0530)
    - The Artist as Advocate, 1993 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0352)
    - Unknown Event -- Vanderbilt Hall, Tishman Auditorium -- Tape 1 Master, Tapes 2-3, 1993-03-13 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0701, 9-8.0704, 9-8.0708, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0709)
    - Unknown Event -- Vanderbilt Hall, Tishman Auditorium -- Tapes 1-4, Tape 3 Master, 1993-04-12 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0698 -- 9-8.0700, 9-8.0702 -- 9-8.0703, 9-8.0705 -- 9-8.0707)
    - Unknown Event -- Vanderbilt Hall, Tishman Auditorium -- Tape 4, 1993-04-12 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0796)
    - Black Thought in Progress -- Ali Mazrui, 1994 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0425)
    - Black Thought in Progress -- Angela Davis, 1994 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0438, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0463)
    - Fatima Legrand, 1994 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0430)
    - Manning Marble -- Columbia University, 1994 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0431)
    - Ph/r/ases -- Lesson 5, 1994 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0171)
    - Wahneema Lubiano -- Bobst Library, 1994 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0422)
    - Black Thought in Progress Lecture Series -- Patricia Hills Collins and Fatima Legrand, 1995 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0421)
    - Black Thought in Progress Lecture Series -- Quincy Troupe, 1995 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0359)
    - Van and TSMN, 1995 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0330)
    - Black Thought in Progress -- Terry McMillan, 1995-02-07 (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0491)
    - Language in African American Diaspora: Evidence from Liberian Settler English about the History of African American Vernacular English -- John Singler, 1995-10-31 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0797)
    - Justice Clarence Thomas in Retrospect -- Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., 1995-11-21 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0236, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0432, Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0506, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0719)
    - Justice Clarence Thomas in Retrospect -- Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr., 1995-11-21 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0798 -- 9-8.0799)
    - Gaston Kaboré -- Tapes 1 and 2, 1995-12-10 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0800 -- 9-8.0801)
    - Home -- Anna Devere Smith and Ntozako Shange, 1996 (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0487)
    - Hortense Spillers and Fatima Legrand, 1996 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0420)
    - Julius Lester and Fatima Legrand, 1996 (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0290)
    - Lost Scholar, 1996 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0220)
    - Sembene R3, circa 1996-1997 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0632)
    - Tishman Auditorium, 1996 (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0306, Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0490)
    - Walter Mosley and Carl Franklin, 1996 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0324, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0426)
    - Unknown Event -- Master -- Tapes 1 and 2, 1996-02-09 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0714 -- 9-8.0715)
    - Friday -- Master, 1996-03-22 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0716)
    - Ben Snow and Glenda Noel-Doyle -- Bobst Library, 1996-04-20 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0342, 9-8.0354, 9-8.0356, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0720 -- 9-8.0722)
    - Unknown Event -- Tapes 1-3, 1996-04-20 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0710 -- 9-8.0712)
    - Robin D.G. Kelley, 1996-04-30 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0726)
    - Word Conference Intro Remarks and Morning Panel I, 1996-09-27 (Box 94, Hi8 9-8.0612)
    - Friday -- Master Tapes 1-2, 1996-10-18 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0724 -- 9-8.0725)
    - Friday -- Master, 1996-11-22 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0635)
    - Tapes 1-2, 1996-11-25 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0717, 9-8.0740)
    - Monday -- Master Tapes 1-2, 1996-12-09 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0633, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0718)
    - Wednesday -- Master Tapes, 1996-12-11 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0634, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0713)
    - 1/2, 1997 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0135)
    - M P G -- Robert C. Banks, 1997 (Box 85, U-matic 9-8.0172)
    - The Eyes of the Rainbow and B Roll, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0170)
    - A Suite of Voices, 1997 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0057 -- 9-8.0059, Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0061)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Haki Madhubuti, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0007, Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0156, 9-8.0164, Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0228)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Angela Davis, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0002 -- 9-8.0003, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0277, Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0489)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Anna Deavere Smith, 1997 (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0262, 9-8.0280, 9-8.0282, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0399)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: bell hooks, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0004 -- 9-8.0005, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0467)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Farai Chideya, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0001, 9-8.0006, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0264, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0398)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: George Curry, 1997 (Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0014 -- 9-8.0015, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0269 -- 9-8.0271, Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0485)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Joycelyn Elders, 1997 (Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0016, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0265, 9-8.0272)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Julianne Malveaux, 1997 (Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0017 -- 9-8.0018, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0278 -- 9-8.0279)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Melvin Van Peebles, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0008, Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0150, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0263, 9-8.0273, 9-8.0281)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Randall Robinson, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0009, Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0147, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0462, Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0486)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Stanley Crouch, 1997 (Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0019 -- 9-8.0020, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0266 -- 9-8.0267, 9-8.0274, 9-8.0276)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Walter Mosley, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0010, Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0021, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0275, 9-8.0298, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0410)
    - Black Genius: Anna Deavere Smith, 1997 (Box 69, Betacam 9-8.0012, Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0022)
    - Compositions -- Ak. Wise Film, 1997 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0409)
    - Conversations with Nancy Morejon, 1997 (Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0066 -- 9-8.0067)
    - B Roll, Casa Italiana -- Tapes 1-2, 1997 (Box 75, Betacam 9-8.0076 -- 9-8.0077)
    - Yande Diop and Maryse Condé; Mason Francois; Felino and Mark -- Tapes 1-2, 1997 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0090 -- 9-8.0091)
    - Mark and Felino, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0151, 9-8.0154)
    - Mark and Felino -- Run Out B Roll, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0157)
    - Mark and Felino -- Friday PM B Roll, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0159)
    - Mark and Felino -- Opening Conference, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0162)
    - Maya Angelou -- Interview with Participant, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0158)
    - Maya Angelou -- Conference ISO Camera -- Tapes 1-2, 1997 (Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0064 -- 9-8.0065)
    - Maya Angelou -- Conference Primary Camera -- Tapes 1-2, 1997 (Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0062 -- 9-8.0063)
    - Men's Panel, 1997 (Box 78, Betacam 9-8.0114 -- 9-8.0115)
    - Yari Yari Conference -- Open Microphone, circa 1997-2004 (Box 75, Betacam 9-8.0078 -- 9-8.0079)
    - Poet's House, 1997 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0155, 9-8.0160, Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0161)
    - Reading with Gloria Naylor and Others, 1997 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0095 -- 9-8.0096)
    - Sekou Toure RDC -- Mole James Martw Cisse, 1997 (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0132)
    - Steve McQueen and Jo'Berg, 1997 (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0175)
    - Street Scene -- Mali and Interviews -- Tape 5, 1997 (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0131)
    - Walter Moseley and Octavia Butler -- Tape 1, 1997 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0087 -- 9-8.0088)
    - Black Genius Forum -- Haki Madhubuti, 1997-01-23 (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0268, 9-8.0289, Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0557)
    - Angela Davis, 1997-02-21 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0518, Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0599)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 1, 1997-02-21 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0727)
    - Thursday -- Master Tapes, 1997-02-27 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0519, 9-8.0560)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 2, 1997-02-27 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0728)
    - Farai Chideya -- Master Tape 1, 1997-03-07 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0533)
    - Friday -- Master Tape 2, 1997-03-07 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0733)
    - bell hooks -- Master Tape 1, 1997-03-10 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0732)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 2, 1997-03-10 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0554)
    - Julianne Malveaux -- Master Tape 1-2, 1997-03-14 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0555 -- 9-8.0556)
    - George Curry -- Tape 1, 1997-03-27 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0522)
    - Monday -- Master Tape 1, 1997-04-14 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0729)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 2, 1997-04-14 (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0730)
    - Anna Deavere Smith -- Tape 1, 1997-04-16 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0521)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 2, 1997-04-16 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0520)
    - Thursday -- Master Tapes 1-2, 1997-04-24 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0559, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0731)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 1, 1997-04-28 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0558)
    - Yari Yari Conference: Black Women Writers and the Future, circa 1997-2004 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0336)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- Black Women Writers and the Future -- Bad Copy, 1997-10-15-1997-10-18 (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0174)
    - Yari Yari Conference -- Conversation with Jayne Cortez and His Excellency Lindiwe Mabuza, 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0049)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Conflicting Forces" -- In Greenberg Lounge, 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0052 -- 9-8.0053)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Dramatic Collaborations" -- Cut Away and Panel CVs, 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0051)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Dramatic Collaborations" -- Podium Camera, 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0050)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Publishing Streams and the Future", 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0055 -- 9-8.0056, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0476, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0738 -- 9-8.0739)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Variations With and Without a Theme", 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0054)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- Conversations with June [?], Nawal El Saadawi, and Kathleen Neal Cleaver, 1997-10-15 (Box 73, Betacam 9-8.0048)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Forced Entries: The Subject of Violence", 1997-10-16 (Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0072, Box 75, Betacam 9-8.0073 -- 9-8.0075, Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0628)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Laws, Customs, Democracy, Literature and the Future" -- Part I-II, 1997-10-16 (Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0070 -- 9.8.0071)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Telling Women's Stories: From Village to Video Journalism", 1997-10-16 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0152 -- 9-8.0153, 9-8.0169)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Critic, the Media, and the People", 1997-10-16; cuid18832
      - Camera 2, Tape #1, cuid18837 (Box 75, Betacam sp 9-8.0080)
        Duration: 63 min
      - Camera 2, Tape #2, cuid18838 (Box 75, Betacam sp 9-8.0081)
        Duration: 36 min
      - Ian's Version, Tape #1, cuid18839 (Box 75, Betacam sp 9-8.0082)
        Duration: 62 min
      - Ian's Version, Tape #2, cuid18840 (Box 75, Betacam sp 9-8.0083)
        Duration: 38 min
      - VHS recording (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0470)
      - Audiocassette (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0734)
      - Audiocassette (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0735)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Turning Point", 1997-10-16 (Box 74, Betacam 9-8.0068 -- 9-8.0069)
    - Yari Yari Conference -- Awards Dinner, 1997-10-17 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0103)
    - Yari Yari Conference -- Closing Plenary Session, 1997-10-17; cuid18833
      - Camera 1, Tape #1, cuid18842 (Box 79, Betacam sp 9-8.0123)
        Duration: 67 min
      - Camera 2, Tape #1, cuid18843 (Box 79, Betacam sp 9-8.0121)
        Duration: 64 min
      - Camera 2, Tape #2, cuid18844 (Box 79, Betacam sp 9-8.0122)
        Duration: 3 min
    - Yari Yari Conference -- Cocktail Reception B Roll, 1997-10-17 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0163)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Beyond Boundaries: Language, Writing, and the Future", 1997-10-17 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0089)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Claiming Identities", 1997-10-17 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0099 -- 9-8.0100, Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0621)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Directions in Literature", 1997-10-17 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0097 -- 9-8.0098)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Freedom of Expression: Censorship and Self-Censorship", 1997-10-17 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0092, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0469, Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0736 -- 9-8.0737)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Imagination, Technology and the Future", 1997-10-17; cuid18834
      - Betacam SP recording, cuid18841 (Box 76, Betacam sp 9-8.0093)
        Duration: 93 min
      - VHS recording (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0329)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Cinema and Women Filmmakers", 1997-10-17; cuid18835 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0086)
      Duration: 73 min
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Nature of Fiction", 1997-10-17 (Box 75, Betacam 9-8.0084)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Next Generation: Truth Be Told", 1997-10-17 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0101 -- 9-8.0102)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Poet and the Power of the Word", 1997-10-17 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0094)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Poetry, the Media, and the Future", 1997-10-17 (Box 76, Betacam 9-8.0085)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Literature for Young People: Shaping the Future", 1997-10-18 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0105)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Lives Revealed: Biography and Autobiography", 1997-10-18 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0108, Box 78, Betacam 9-8.0109 -- 9-8.0113)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Men Writers Discuss Women Writers, Literature, and the Future", 1997-10-18 (Box 78, Betacam 9-8.0116 -- 9-8.0117)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Right to Read and Write", 1997-10-18 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0104)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Creative Process and Economic Issues in Publishing", 1997-10-18 (Box 78, Betacam 9-8.0119 -- 9-8.0120)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "The Girl Child: Education, Health, Literature and the Future", 1997-10-18 (Box 77, Betacam 9-8.0106 -- 9-8.0107)
    - Yari Yari Conference Panel -- "Visual-Verbal Connection", 1997-10-18; cuid18836
      - B-roll, Tape 1 (Box 78, Betacam sp 9-8.0118)
      - B-roll, Tape 2, cuid18845 (Box 84, Betacam sp 9-8.0168)
        Duration: 19 min
    - Untitled, 1997-12-14 (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0187)
    - What Time is It for Black Youth and Black Theater and Film Music -- Artist-in-Residence, 1998 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0039 -- 9-8.0040, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0295)
    - Africana Studies Readings, 1998 (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0293, 9-8.0478, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0427, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0473, 9-8.0479)
    - Artist in Residence: Amiri Baraka, 1998 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0167)
    - Black Genius: Building Self-Sustaining Societies, 1998 (Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0013, Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0042, Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0252, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0435 -- 9-8.0436)
    - Black Genius: Biracial Visions of America, 1998 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0140, 9-8.0043, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0292, 9-8.0434, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0434)
    - Black Theater and Film Music -- Artist in Residence, 1998 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0036 -- 9-8.0037)
    - Celebration of Margaret Walker, 1998 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0038, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0296)
    - International Standards of Beauty, 1998 (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0464)
    - Unknown Event, January 1998 (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0493)
    - NYU Celebrates Africana Studies, 1998 (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0480)
    - Panel on Toussaint Louverture, 1998 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0325, 9-8.0351)
    - Strategy and Tactics of Black Liberation and American Revolution, 1998 (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0124, Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0142, Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0166, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0283)
    - The Artist as Advocate, 1998 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0143, Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0339)
    - Thulani Davis, 1998 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0350)
    - Umbra Re-Emergence: Tribute to Tom Dent, 1998 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0248 -- 9-8.0249)
    - Umbra 2, circa 1998 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0335, Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0492)
    - Wednesday (Master) -- Tapes 1-3, 1998-03-04 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0802 -- 9-8.0804)
    - Glenda Noel--Doyle, 1998-03-11 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0805)
    - Sidime Laye and Maryse Condé -- Tape 2, circa 1998-1999 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0134)
    - 3rd Anniversary Open Element Globe, 1999 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0146)
    - African Studies: Thulani Davis, 1999 (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0125, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0419, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0472)
    - Artist in Residence: Wole Soyinka, 1999 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0041, Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0340 -- 9-8.0341)
    - Black Genius Series Speaker: Jocelyn Elders, 1999 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0377)
    - Cut 9, 1999 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0254)
    - Democracy in Africa -- Wole Soyinka, Anthony Appiah, Manthia Diawara, and White, 1999 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0141, Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0145, Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0326, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0437)
    - Diaspora Conversations: From Goree to Dogon, 1999 (Box 70, Betacam 9-8.0023, Box 86, Vhs 9-8.0191 -- 9-8.0218, Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0344, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0428 -- 9-8.0429, 9-8.0439 -- 9-8.0440, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0441 -- 9-8.0454)
    - Leota NYU '99, 1999 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0365)
    - New Excerpts, 1999 (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0466)
    - Yari Yari Conference -- II, 1999 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0337)
    - Wole Soyinka -- Tape 1, Side A, 1999-02-17 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0563)
    - African American Award -- Tape 2, 1999-02-18 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0561)
    - Wole Soyinka -- Tape 2, 1999-02-19 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0562)
    - Africana Studies: Thulani Davis, 1999-03-26 (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0829)
    - Geffen Home Video -- B Roll, 1999-06-10 (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0188)
    - B-Roll, 1999-09-27 (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0185)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Opening Plenary, Part I-II, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0026 -- 9-8.0029)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Awards Dinner and Fundraiser, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0047)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Middle Passage, Part II, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0025)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Culture and Slavery, Part II, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0031)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Distribution of the Enslaved, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0044)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Expressions and Documentation of The Route, Part I-II, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0035, Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0060)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Impact of Slave Trade on African Society, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0030)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: New York City African Burial Ground, Part I-II, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 72, Betacam 9-8.0045 -- 9-8.0046)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Origins of the Slaves, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0024)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Women and Slavery, Part I-II, and Resistance, Part I, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0032 -- 9-8.0033)
    - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Panel: Resistance, Part II, 1999-10-05-1999-10-09 (Box 71, Betacam 9-8.0034)
    - DF Basic VTRIII, 1999-2000 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0148)
    - Salif Kaita Panel Discussion, circa 2000 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0259 -- 9-8.0260)
    - A Conversation Between Jean Rouch and Manthia Diawara, 2000 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0381)
    - African Film Festival, 2000 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0322, 9-8.0338)
    - An Evening of Traditional Music -- Salif Keita, 2000 (Box 85, Dvcam 9-8.0182)
    - Bamboozled Panel Discussion: Electronic Press Kit, 2000 (Box 85, U-matic 9-8.0173)
    - Documentary: Diaspora Conversations: From Goree to Dogon -- Danny Glover, circa 2000 (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0288)
    - Danny Glover Arrives in Africa and Meets..., circa 2000 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0362)
    - W.E.B Dubois Lecture: David L. Lewis, 2000 (Box 85, Dvcam 9-8.0181, 9-8.0183, Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0237)
    - NYU Concert, 2000 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0242, 9-8.0261, Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0285)
    - Robert Banks Short Films, 2000 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0137)
    - Salif Keita, 2000 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0379)
    - Salif Keita and Quincy Troupe, 2000 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0382 -- 9-8.0383)
    - Salif Keita Concert, 2000 (Box 85, Dvcam 9-8.0184)
    - Haiti on Screen -- Panel Discussion 1 and 2, circa 2000-2005 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0613 -- 9-8.0614)
    - Haiti on Screen -- Saturday Panel, circa 2000-2005 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0348)
    - Jayne Cortez, 2000-03-01 (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0778 -- 9-8.0779)
    - Jayne Cortez and Abby Lincoln, 2000-03-07 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0331 -- 9-8.0332, Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0670)
    - African Film Festival, 2000-05-20 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0572 -- 9-8.0573)
    - African Film Festival, 2000-05-21 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0507, 9-8.0512)